Inventory of the Papers of Judge Pierce Lively 1972-1997
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Papers of Judge Pierce Lively 1972-1997
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 98-2
This collection contains 50 boxes of files (21 linear feet).
The Papers of Judge Pierce Lively document his service on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit from 1972-1997. In addition to selected case files the collection contains documentation of judicial administration and committee work.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Pierce Lively was born in Louisville, Kentucky, on August 17, 1921 to Ruby Keating and Henry Thaddeus Lively, a lawyer. He studied at Centre College in Danville, where he graduated magna cum laude with a B.A. in History and English Literature. From 1943 to 1946 he served in the U.S. Navy and while in the service married his college sweetheart, Amelia Harrington. After the war he studied law at the University of Virginia where he served on the editorial board of the Law Review and received the honors of membership in the Order of the Coif and the Raven Society.
After graduating in 1948, he returned to Kentucky. He first clerked for U.S. Sixth Circuit Judge Shackelford Miller, Jr. in Louisville, and then settled in Danville where he practiced law for twenty-two years. In 1958 he formed a partnership with Nelson Rhodes, and together they specialized in litigation, tax law, and business counseling. At one point Lively sat as a special trial judge of the Boyle Circuit Court during the illness of Judge Kendrick S. Alcorn. Aside from his law practice Lively served the community in a number of other ways. In 1952 he joined the Board of Trustees of Centre College and has since been appointed a trustee for life. During the sixties and seventies, he was a member of the biracial Human Relations Council, the Kentucky Commission on Economy and Efficiency in Government, and the Kentucky Judicial Advisory Committee.
On September 12, 1972, he was appointed by President Nixon to the Sixth Circuit and served as chief judge of that court from 1983 to 1988. At the time of his retirement Lively noted that a number of the cases he had heard were "pacesetting" cases in areas such as abortion rights, affirmative action, desegregation, environmental protection, free speech and separation of church and state.. A former law clerk, J. Kevin Buster, characterized Lively as "an old-fashioned Republican. He's for the little guy, for individual rights, [and] established himself as a fiery defender of civil liberties, using his power to restrain governments and religions from forcing themselves on individuals." In Lively's words: "Some of the worst abuses in human history have been committed by governments in the name of religion. Our Founding Fathers wisely understood this and acted to prevent it, in no uncertain terms, in the Constitution." Lexington Herald-Leader, A12, January 4, 1998.
Judge Lively was a role model for his clerks and staff. In 1989 when his portrait was presented to the Court in Cincinnati, his former law clerk Kay Randall spoke at the ceremony. She concluded her remarks by saying, "Judge Lively continues to demonstrate all of those qualities which so impressed me as a young clerk: integrity, experience, judicial temperament, scholarship, and a love of the law, and also the human qualities of fairness, compassion and patience. With all of these qualities, the Judge has earned our respect and admiration." 946 F.2d cxxiv.
Judge Lively took senior status in January 1989 and retired from the bench December 31, 1997.
Scope and Content Information
Judge Lively donated his papers to the University of Virginia Law Library in January of 1998. In a letter dated January 22, he described the papers he was sending to the library:
... the office files [contain] cases in which I wrote either a majority or dissenting opinion. There are relatively few case files from the earliest years of my tenure on the court, because many files of that period were discarded routinely. More recently, since it has come to my attention that the archives would be interested, I have retained many more files. These files, while of varying importance, serve to illustrate the broad range of subject matter dealt with by the United States Court of Appeals. The files also illustrate my particular way of working. Each file contains my notes at the hearing and most contain both a pre-hearing and a post-hearing memorandum by a law clerk. I wrote by hand a draft of each opinion and after it was typed out, a copy was given to a law clerk who worked with me in producing the final draft....
I did not include case files from any of the cases where the court issued an unpublished opinion. As our docket grew, we considered more and more cases without oral argument and these usually produced unpublished opinions. The cases in which we issued such unpublished opinions were usually quite routine and repetitive or were totally fact-specific.
While he served on the bench, Judge Lively performed many administrative duties for his circuit, as well as for the Judicial Conference. For the latter, he served on the Advisory Committee on Federal Rules for Appellate Procedure (FRAP) and the Standing Committee of Rules of Practice and Procedure. The Sixth Circuit administrative work as well as these committee activities are documented in the collection.
Organization
The Lively papers have been kept in the order in which they were received, and his folder headings have been preserved. The 50 boxes (21 linear feet) of files are organized in these groups:
Selected Case Files, 1972-97, Boxes 1 - 32, including Mozert v. Hawkins County Board of Education, a book banning case which alleged violation of First Amendment rights to exercise of religion; Detroit Police Officers' Association v. Young, an affirmative action case; City of Akron v. Akron Center for Reproductive Health, Inc., an abortion case which addressed the state's ability to regulate the abortion procedure; and Demjanjuk v. Petrovsky, the case concerning the deportation to Israel of an alleged Nazi prison guard.
Sixth Circuit Administrative Files, predominantly 1980s, Boxes 32 - 40, organized by the judge into these categories: general administrative, court and council meetings, chief judge -- general, and chief judge -- bankruptcy.
Judicial Conference, Boxes 41 - 47, arranged in three categories: General, 1976-9; Standing Committee on Rules of Practice and Procedure, 1987-89; and Advisory Committee on Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure, 1979-90.
Correspondence, Speeches, etc. and Miscellany, 1973-97, Boxes 47-49.
Published Materials, 1984-89, Box 50.
Contents List
- Case Files:
- No. 91-6353. Adkins, Margie Jo v. Board of Education of Magoffin County, Kentucky and Carter Whitaker as superintendent. 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- No. 90-3047. Aetna Life and Casualty Co. v. Huntington National Bank. 1991 (Box 1)
- Nos. 79-3700/01 and 79-3757. Akron Center for Reproductive Health v. City of Akron. 1980, 3 folders (Box 1)
- No. 89-1889. Allstate Insurance Company v. Mercier, Mair and others. 1990 (Box 1)
- No. 84- 1637. American Civil Liberties Union v. City of Birmingham, Michigan. 1980 (Box 1)
- No. 81-5316. American Fidelity Bank & Trust Co., et al v. John Heimann, Comptroller, et al. 1982 (Box 2)
- No. 86-1860. Americans United for Separation of Church and State, et al, Phyllis Ball, et al v. The School District of the City of Grand Rapids, et al. 1987-1988 (Box 2)
- Nos. 90-2337, 91-1448, 91-1391. Americans United for Separation of Church and State, et al v. City of Grand Rapids v. Chabad House of Western Michigan, Inc. Nos. 90-2337, 91-1448, 91-1391. 1992 (Box 2)
- Nos. 90-2337, 91-1391 II. Americans United for Separation of Church and State, Benjamin Baum, Phillis Ball, Walter Bergman; John Charles Bearden; Gilbert R. Davies and James T. Weaver v. City of Grand Rapids, MI, Chabad House of Western Michigan, Inc. 1990-1993 (Box 2)
- No. 89-2393. The Anspec Company, Inc. And Hugh Montgomery v. Johnson Controls, Inc., Hoover Universal, Inc., Hoover Group, Inc. And Ultraspherics, Inc. 1989-1990 (Box 2)
- No. 94-1875. Anusbigian, Michael K. v. TrueGreen/Chemlawn, Inc. 1994-1995 (Box 3)
- Nos. 87-3568/88-3411/87-415. Re: Arkamel Sales v. R. C. Marshall, et al and William Hunter v. Huey Blair, et al. 1989 (Box 3)
- No. 83-3384. Austin, Amy v. Brown Local School District, et al. 1984 (Box 3)
- No. 94-2237. Baca, Antonio J. v. Bruce King, et al. 1993-1996 (Box 3)
- No. 92-5107. Bank One v. Woolum. 1992 (Box 3)
- No. 74-201, No. 74-2020. Big Rivers Electric Corporation, et al v. Tennessee Valley Authority v. EPA. 1975 (Box 3)
- Nos. 76-2149 and 76-2294. Blaylock, Gary, et al v. Cheker Oil C. 1976 (Box 3)
- No. 85-6109. Boddy, Pinkie v. Charles Dean et al. 1987 (Box 3)
- No. 91-1222. Boger, Diane v. Wayne County, MI, Vernice Davis-Anthony. 1991 (Box 3)
- No. 83-1773. Boyton v. TRW, Inc. 1988 (Box 4)
- No. 75-1244. Bronson, Mona et al v. Board of Education of City School District of Cincinnati, et al. 1975 (Box 4)
- No. 91-3597. Buck v. U.S. Department of Agriculture. 1992 (Box 4)
- No. 80-1412. Butler, Robert C. v. Jim Rose, warden. 1982 (Box 4)
- No. 87-5275. Calvert Investments v. Louisville & Jefferson County Sewer, et al. 1988 (Box 4)
- No. 73-1081. Cantrell, Margaret v. Forest City Publishing. 1973 (Box 5)
- No. 89-5341. Carver v. Knox County v. Ned Ray McWherter, et al. 1989 (Box 5)
- No. 92-3952. Charash, Helen v. Oberlin College. 1992-1994 (Box 5)
- Nos. 89-6416/17. In Re: Chattanooga Wholesale Antiques, Inc., Still v. Rossville Bank. 1991 (Box 5)
- No. 90-1233, 81-3292. Cherokee Express v. Cherokee Express. 1990 (Box 5)
- No. 92-5566. Circuit City Store, Inc. v. Pioneer Investment Services Co. 1992-1993 (Box 4)
- No. 86-3140. Cleveland Newspaper Guild v. Plain Dealer Publishing. 1987 (Box 5)
- No. 92-1139. Cline, Boyd L. v. U.S. 1992-1993 (Box 5)
- No. 81-3292. Coastal Tank Lines, Inc. v. ICC. Interstate Commerce Commission. No. 81-3292. 1982 (Box 6)
- No. 92-4016. Congregation Luvavitch Rabbi Shalom B. Kalmanson v. City of Cincinnati. 1992-1993 (Box 6)
- No. 89-1036. Cottages Savings Association v. Commissioners of Internal Revenue. No. 89-1036. 1989 (Box 6)
- No. 88-1079. Dalm, Frances L. v. U.S. 1988 (Box 6)
- No. 83-1378. Day, James v. Wayne county Board of Auditors, et al. 1984 (Box 6)
- No. 85-3435. Demjanjuk, John v. Joseph Petrovsky, et al. 1985, 1992 (Box 7 - 12)
- No. 89-1167. Desonier v. Sullivan, Secretary of Health and Human Services. 1989-1990 (Box 13)
- No. 78-1163. Detroit Police Officers Association, et al v. Coleman A. Young, Mayor of the City of Detroit, et al. 1979 (Box 13)
- No. 82-1890. Detroit, Toledo and Ironton Railroad Company and Grand Trunk Western v. Consolidated Rail Corporation. 1983 (Box 13)
- No. 8413-67. Detroit, Toledo and Ironton Railroad Company and Grand Trunk Western v. Consolidated Rail Corporation. 1985 (Box 13)
- No. 78-1056. Doe, Joe and Jane, Thomas B. Grost and Cora Grost v. Cathy E. Irwin, et al. No. 78-1056 1979-1980 (Box 13)
- Nos. 82-3617-28. Dowling, Steven et al v. Richardson-Merril, Inc. 1983 (Box 13)
- No. 72-1892/3. Dunlop Co. v. Kelsey - Hayes Co. 1973 (Box 13)
- Nos. 87-6102/03/04. Duvoisin v. Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.. 1988 (Box 14)
- Nos. 92-2009/92-2539. Echlin, Raymond Joseph, Ronald Bishop, Donald Johnson v. Robert LeCureux. 1992-1993 (Box 14)
- Nos. 74-1007/08/09 and 74-1675. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission v. The Detroit Edison Co. 1974-1977 (Box 14)
- No. 88-5711. Estate of Minnie Hale v. U.S. 1989 (Box 14)
- No. 77-0021. Ewing, John et al v. Kentucky High School Athletic Association. 1976-1977 (Box 14)
- No. 89-3236. Friedreich, Michael J. v. Secretary of Health and Human Services. 1990 (Box 14)
- No. 86-4114. Farmer, Laura v. Lawrence Rogers. 1987 (Box 14)
- No. 91-6087. Fausek, Thomas A. J. v. Robert E. White. 1992 (Box 15)
- No. 94-2161. Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation v. Prince George Corporation, et al. 1994-1995 (Box 15)
- No.96-1207. Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation v. William K. Rahn and Franklin H. Smith, et al. 1996-1997 (Box 15)
- No. 94-4108. Ferndale Laboratories, Inc. v. Robert D. Cavendish, et al Members of the Ohio State Board of Pharmacy. 1994-1996 (Box 15)
- No.94-3200. Foy, Cynthia D. v. City of Berea, Oh., James H. Hinners, et al. No.94-3200 1994-1995 (Box 15)
- Nos. 93-3285/3286/ 94-1190. Gamma-10 Plastics, Inc. v. American President Lines, Ltd., American President Companies, Ltd. 1993-1994 (Box 15)
- No. 75-2114. Garrett, Sarah Sims, et al v. City of Hamtramck, et al. 1975 (Box 15)
- No. 73-1862. Garrett, Sarah S. et al v. U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, et al. 1974 (Box 16)
- No. 87-1488. Gaunlett, Roger v. Frank Kelley. 1987 (Box 16)
- No. 85-3466. Glen Back v. Benefits Review Board. 1986 (Box 16)
- No. 83-1165. Glen Eden Hospital v. Blue Cross-Blue Shield. 1984 (Box 16)
- No. 76-2204. Gordon, Harold v. City of Warren, MI. 1978 (Box 16)
- No. 83-5508. In Re: Grand Jury Empaneled March 18, 1983. 1983 (Box 16)
- Nos. 95-1940/41. Green, Rose Mary et al v. Larry Nevers, et al. 1997 (Box 16)
- No. 84-6055. Grier, Rita v. Lamar Alexander. 1986 (Box 16)
- No. 77-1148. Hall, Hattie v. HEW. 1978 (Box 17)
- No. 93-3056. Harris, John v. City of Akron, et al. 1993-1994 (Box 17)
- No.94-6042. Harrison, Robert Dale v. Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County, TN and Board of Health. 1995-1996 (Box 17)
- No. 90-6585. Heflin, Allen D. et al v. Stewart County, TN, David Hicks, Joe Henry Crutcher and Wanda Luffman. 1992 (Box 17)
- No. 79-3635. Hill, Donald and Ronald v. The Duriron Company, Inc. 1981 (Box 17)
- No. C76-0353 L(4). Howe, Delbert et al v. Margarite Younger, et al. No. C76-0353 L(4). 1976 (Box 17)
- Nos. 92-3276, 92-1717. Charter Township of Huron, MI v. Thomas C. Richards, Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, et al, City of Dearborn, MI v. Richards, et al. 1992-1993 (Box 11)
- No. 72-1386. International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 369 & Jesse Horges v. Olin Corporation. 1972 (Box 18)
- Nos. 94-6349/6351. International Union, United Automobile Aerospace & Agricultural Implement Worker of America, Local 737; Martha Poston; Virginia Ligon; et al v. Auto Glass Employees Federal Credit Union; National Credit Union Administration Board, et al. 1994-1996 (Box 18)
- No. 8805634. Jackson, Robert and Robert Gettys v. The Law Firm of O=Hara et al. 1989 (Box 18)
- No. 83-3128. Jet Courier Service, et al v. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta, et al. 1983 (Box 18)
- No. 83-5097. Jones, Doyle v. Al C. Parken, Warden. 1983 (Box 18)
- No. 72-1485. In the Matter of KDI Corporation. 1972-1973 (Box 18)
- No. 92-4064. Kelly, Michael P. and John T. Kelly v. The Secretary, US Department of Housing and Urban Development and Dionne Staples. 1992-1993 (Box 18)
- Nos. 95-3107/4141. Kelly, Michael P. and John T. Kelly v. The Secretary, US Department of Housing and Urban Development and Dionne Staples. 1995-1996 (Box 18)
- No. 76-1095. Krause, Arthur et al v. James Rhodes, et al. 1977 (Box 19)
- No.92-5631. Landgraf, Patricia v. McDonnell Douglas Helicopter Co., et al. 1993 (Box 19)
- No. 85-3471. Leaman, Mary v. Ohio Department of Mental Retardation. 1986 (Box 19)
- No. 95-1930. Lochman, Carl; Elaine Lochman in behalf of Kelly and Kyle Lochman v. County of Charlevoix, MI. and Philo Sumner. 1995-1996 (Box 19)
- Nos. 85-1684 and 86-1599. In Re: Long Distance Telecommunications Litigation. 1987 (Box 19)
- No. 93-1891. Mackey, Wendell Shane v. Dennis Dyke, Assistant Deputy Director of the Bureau of Correctional Facilities, MI. 1993-1994 (Box 19)
- No. 94-1607. Malone & Hyde, Inc. and Subdividers v. Commissioner of Internal Revenue. 1994-1995 (Box 20)
- No. 90-3558. Mallory v. Eyrich. 1990 (Box 20)
- No. 46-4195. Mararri v. WCI Steel, Inc. 1996-1997 (Box 20)
- No. 88-5477. Masters, Karen B. v. Bobby C. Crouch, et al. 1989 (Box 20)
- No. 95-3919. In Re: Robert C. McCafferty, Debtor v. Marion McCafferty. 1995-1996 (Box 20)
- No. 86-1008. Estate of A. McCoy v. Commissioner of Internal Revenue. 1986 (Box 20)
- No. 95-2234/ 2269/ 96-1017. McPhearson, Douglas C. and Connie K. v. Arthur T. Kelsey, Thomas Scott and Richard Boushong, Steve Sowle and G. Michael Hocking. 1995-1997 (Box 20)
- No. 86-1239. Michigan Road Builders Association v. William G. Milliken. 1988, 3 folders (Box 21)
- No. 95-1114. Monette, Roger and Doris v. Electronic Data Systems Corporation. 1995-1996 (Box 21)
- No. 84-5235. In Re: Morgansten, David and Fred Grand Jury Proceedings. 1985 (Box 21)
- Nos. 89-3473/3475. Mosley, Phillis v. Roland Hairston, Director of Ohio Department of Human Services, et al. 1989-1990 (Box 21)
- No. 90-1496. Moses v. Business Card Express, Inc. 1991 (Box 21)
- Nos. 86-6144/79, 86-6180, 87-5024. Mozert, Bob and Alicia v. Hawkins County, TN Board of Education. 1987, 3 folders (Box 22)
- No. 73-1686. National Steel Corporation v. Kinsman Marine Transit. 1973 (Box 22)
- No. 82-1513. Nichols, Roland and Gaylene v. Toledo Equipment Company, Inc. 1983 (Box 22)
- No. 79-1145. NLRB [National Labor Relations Board] v. Unit Train Coal Sales, Inc. 1980 (Box 22)
- Nos. 92-5265/66/68. Ockerman, Fred v. May Zima Company, et al. 19592-1994 (Box 23)
- No. 82-3822. Ohio Contractors Association v. William Keip and National Association of Minority Contractors. 1983 (Box 23)
- No. 74-1203. Olympic Fastening Systems v. Textron. 1974 (Box 23)
- No. 74-1496. Orleans, Joseph V. v. U.S. 1974-19755 (Box 23)
- No. 78-1140. Parke, Davis and Co. v. Joseph Califano, Secretary of HEW [Health, Education and Welfare]. 1980 (Box 23)
- No. 80-3231. Pate, James v. Steve Smith, et al. 19805 (Box 23)
- No. 94-1028. Peacock, John C. v. Landquest Limited, et al. 1994-1995 (Box 23)
- No. 96-3890. Penny, James R. v. United Parcel Service. 1996-1997 (Box 23)
- No. 90-3953. Petkiewytsch, Leonid v. Immigration and Naturalization Service. 1991 (Box 23)
- No. 86-1423. Pilarowsky, John v. Macomb County Health Department, et al. 1987 (Box 24)
- No. 84-3332. Polo Fashions, Inc., et al v. Stock Byers International, etc. 1985 (Box 24)
- No. 95-1402. Raddatz, Matthew Eric and Jessey Wayne Raddatz (child) v. Shonie Beaubien, et al. 1995-1996 (Box 24)
- No. 82-5028. Ranger Insurance Co. v. Knox Equipment Inc. 1982 (Box 24)
- No. 72-1519. Redmon, Mildred v. U.S. [First Opinion of Judge Lively]. 1972 (Box 24)
- No. 78-3218. Reed, Robert Anthony et al v. Cleveland Board of Education. 1978 (Box 24)
- No. 78-3520/3522. Reed, Robert Anthony et al v. Cleveland Board of Education. 1979 (Box 24)
- No. 80-3574. Reed, Robert Anthony et al v. Cleveland Board of Education. 1980 (Box 24)
- Nos. 79-3131. Reed, Robert Anthony et al v. Cleveland Board of Education. No. 79-3132. Reed, Robert Anthony, et al v. Ohio Board of Education. 1980 (Box 24)
- Nos. 81-3417/18. Reed, Robert A. et al v. James A. Hodes, et al v. Ohio State Board of Education, et al. 1982 (Box 24)
- No. 78-1154. Reminga, Gertrude v. U.S. 1980 (Box 25)
- No. 93-3884. Reynolds, Harry L. Jr. v. International Amateur Athletic Association, The Athletic Congress, et al. 1993-1994 (Box 25)
- No. 82-3218. Rowland, Marjorie v. Mad River Local School District, Montgomery County, OH, a public school corporation, et al. 1983 (Box 25)
- No. 86-4158, 873005. Schrand, Carl v. Federal Pacific Electric. 1988 (Box 25)
- No. 80-1090. Schultz, Leonard v. Newsweek, Inc. and The Evening News Association. No. 80-1090. 1981 (Box 25)
- No. 88-1980. Schwartz v. Electronic Data System. 1990 (Box 25)
- No. 79-1633. Sequoyah, Ammoneta v. Tennessee Valley Authority. 1979 (Box 25)
- No. 74-1823. Shack, Charles v. Charles Southworth, at al. 1974-1975 (Box 26)
- Nos. 93-3239, 93-4087. Sims, Debra and Lyle Stephens v. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration; U.S. Department of Transportation and Federico Pena. 1993-1994 (Box 26)
- No. 95-4261. Smith, Sandra S. v. Ted W. Sushka. 1995-1997 (Box 26)
- No. 79-3352. Southern Ohio Building Systems, Inc. v. US Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission. 1981 (Box 26)
- No. 94-3850, 94-3932. Stacey, Ted v. Richard S. Fraser and William D. Koehler. 1992-1996 (Box 26)
- Nos. 91-1901/02. State of Michigan and U.S. Environmental Protection Agency v. The City of Allen Park, MI, et al. 1992 (Box 26)
- No. 84-3667. State of Ohio v. William D. Ruckelshaus, Environmental Protection Agency. 1985 (Box 26)
- No. 84-3181. State of Ohio, et al v. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Health Case Financing Administration. 1985 (Box 26)
- No. 83-57-47. Storey, Robert et al v. Local 326, International Brotherhood, etc. 1985 (Box 26)
- No. 95-9528. Teamsters Local Union No. 435 v. National Labor Relations Board. 1995-1996 (Box 26)
- No. 90-5945. Tennessee Asphalt Company, et al v. Robert E. Farris, et al. 1990-1991 (Box 27)
- No. 78-3054. Tolar, Michael v. Kinsman Marine Transit. 1980 (Box 27)
- No. 87-5245. Traub, Gordon v. Commonwealth of Kentucky. 1987 (Box 27)
- No. 80-1572. Tuohy, Jerome F. v. Ford Motor Company. 1982 (Box 27)
- No. 81-1681. United Coin Meter Co. v. Seaboard Coastline Railroad. 1983 (Box 27)
- No. 89-3912. United Steelworkers of America v. New Idea Farm Equipment Corporation. 1989-1990 (Box 27)
- No. 89-3344. United Transportation Union v. CSX Transportation, Inc. 1989-1990 (Box 27)
- No. 79-1342. Universal Electrical Co. v. A. O. Smith Corporation. 1980 (Box 27)
- No. 77-1621. University of Tennessee v. Rita Geir, et al. 1978 (Box 27)
- No. 75-2477. U.S. v. Fred Abraham, et al. 1975 (Box 27)
- No. 91-5314. U.S. v. Terry Keith Arthur. 1991-1992 (Box 27)
- Nos. 90-1978/79/98/99. U.S. v. Bakke, Rau, Morris and Deuries. 1991-1992 (Box 28)
- No. 93-5017. U.S. v. Cecil Borroughs, Jr. 1993 (Box 28)
- No. 84-3737. U.S. v. John Charles Blankenship. 1985 (Box 28)
- No. 89-3136. U.S. v. Michael Bryant. 1989-1990 (Box 28)
- Nos. 95-3242, 95-3513. U.S. v. Anthony Caicedo and William A. Ryan. 1995-1996 (Box 28)
- No. 81-3031. U.S. v. City of Parma, Ohio. 1981 (Box 28)
- Nos. 73-1876-83. U.S. v. James Dye, et al. 1973-1974 (Box 28)
- Nos. 90-6589/90. U.S. v. James Lee Evans. 1991 (Box 28)
- Nos. 88-5392, 85-5528. Re: U.S. v. William K. Frazier and Mark B. DeBusk. 1989 (Box 28)
- No. 96-1339. U.S. v. Leslie A. Grable. 1996 (Box 29)
- No. 70-5036. U.S. v. William James, Jr. 1983 (Box 29)
- No. 95-6218. U.S. v. Gilbert Antonio Jarquin. 1995-1996 (Box 29)
- No. 78-5288. U.S. v. James Love. 1979 (Box 29)
- No. 95-3794. U.S. v. Thomas A. Malcuit. 1995-1997 (Box 29)
- No. 75-2121. U.S. v. One 1975 Mercury 4-Door Automobile, Maroon in Color, etc. 1976 (Box 29)
- No. 91-5581. U.S. v. Nichols. 1992 (Box 29)
- Nos. 94-1364, 94-1553. U.S. v. Anthony James Palazzolo and Richard Rosenbaum. 1994-1995 (Box 29)
- No. 95-2169. U.S. v. John A. Rapanos. 1995-1997 (Box 29)
- No. 94-1032ND. U.S. v. Dennis B. Sather, Jr. 1994 (Box 30)
- No. 82-5200. U.S. v. Leslie B. Schlansky. 1983 (Box 30)
- No. 93-248. U.S. v. James Spinelle. 1993-1994 (Box 30)
- No. 94-4117. U.S. v. Gregory Surrat. 1994-1996 (Box 30)
- No. 86-5409. U.S. v. Howard Underhill, et al. No. 86-5412. U.S. v. Pat Tata, et al. 1986 (Box 30)
- Nos. 73-1588-1593. U.S. v. Wac, Dennis, et al. 1974 (Box 30)
- No. 89-5494. U.S. v. Warner Bros. Well Drilling. 1990 (Box 30)
- No. 75-1347. U.S. v. Anthony Williams. 1974-1975 (Box 30)
- No. 85-1324. Utica Packing v. Robert Bergland, Secretary of US Department of Agriculture. 1985 (Box 30)
- No. 80-3351. Van Curen, George D. v. A. R. Jago, et al. 1980 (Box 30)
- No. 83-1368. Vaughn, Mendell et al v. The City of Flint. 1984 (Box 30)
- Nos. 90-2249, 91-1273. Virtual Maintenance Inc. v. Prime Computer, Inc. 1993 (Box 31)
- No. 89-3331. Warren, Robert v. Society National Bank. 1990 (Box 31)